# Abishek Kanageswaran

## **SKILLS**

HTML/CSS Figma (Designing) JavaScript (ES6+, NodeJS, React, Redux, jQuery)

### **EDUCATION**

Franklin University B.S. in Web Development GPA 3.0 + April 2016 - May 2021 Columbus, OH

## **CONTACT**

⊠ Abishekkanageswaran70@gmail.com

in http://www.linkedin.com/in/abishek1718

**(** (614) – 701 – 8131

https://www.Abishek.fyi

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Front End Developer with a passion for website development and success in managing development projects. Experienced in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React JS. Proficient in translating UI/UX design wireframes to actual code, creating user interfaces, and integrating front-end aspects of application while ensuring maximum stability.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **CelebratingOne - Non-Profit Organization (Volunteer)**

Website Designer - May 2021 - Present.

- Proposed and implemented new site content architecture and navigation scheme for company website redesign.
- Responsible for designing mockups, wireframes, and building the website.
- Coordinate various web pages with appropriate links and multimedia elements in collaboration with design team members.
- Handling all compositions, color, illustration, typography, and branding.

#### Franklin University

Student Registrar Assistant - March 2018 - Present, Ohio (3 years +)

- Responsible for providing support to the Registrar Department procedures, such as Scanning official transcripts/Document into the system.
- Managed and organized student transcripts for transferring students to ensure all transcripts are accurate.
- Record transfer credit, advance placement, and grade changes.
- Maintain accurate student records to compliance regulation.

## **PROJECTS**

Fair Lanka (https://www.fairlanka.info)

- Built a website for a wholesale & Retail company from scratch.
- Display Information about the business model, what company offers, Hours of operation and a contact form for more discussion.
- Tools Used: HTML/CSS, React JS & Netlify

Movie Database App (https://zen-einstein-67ea59.netlify.app/)

- Build a Movie Database App like IMDb Website.
- Display recent movies, story line, ratings & search for favorite movies.
- Tools Used: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.